STEPHEN KNOTT

UI Designer / Front-End Developer

I am an accomplished UI Designer with a strong project management background, specializing in designing interactive web applications, utilizing current practices in HTML, CSS, responsive design and conducting usability tests. My experience in concept development, wireframes, design, and front-end development allows me to understand user intentions across various online platforms.

Experience

Iora Health | Boston, MA

January 2016 - October 2016

UI Developer

- Designed and developed front-end architecture for Iora's in-house electronic medical records software "Chirp".
- Planned and collaborate Chirp's CSS framework which was built from the ground up.
- Conducted and gathered research for usability testing of low-fi prototypes using new software designs with various practice members ranging from nurses, health coaches, and doctors.

Ace Ticket Worldwide, Inc. | Boston, MA

September 2012 - January 2016

UI Designer / Front-End Developer

- Design current front-end for Aceticket.com and Ace Ticket mobile, which has garnered positive reviews by users such as "easy to use", and helped to increase overall conversion goals from 2012-2014 by 3%.
- Planned, collaborated, and designed multiple Ace Ticket co-branded web applications including Boston.com's ticket portal, Tickets for Charity, and Ace Concierge used by local Boston hotels.
- Create and manage cohesive online marketing and print campaigns including banner ads, responsive email templates, and mass marketing mediums.

Lachance Design, LLC | Lowell, MA

July 2008 - September 2012

Web Designer / Developer / Contractor

- Managed design and implementation of wireframes into dynamic web applications for Senior Living industry in cities of Boston and Philadelphia.
- Collaborated with Marketing Directors of various Senior Care management facilities to create and promote brand identity to be used in both web and print media.
- Analyzed user traffic data to improve overall user experience, navigation paths, and increased clients' conversion goals with web applications.

Education

BFA, Graphic/Web Design | University of Massachusetts, Lowell

Conducting Usability Testing | Interaction Design Foundation

June 2016

References, trainings, and user reviews available upon request